Kitasan.
北部
Morning.
早安
You're training hard today as well.
今天也很拼呢
Have you decided on which race is next?
下一场比赛已经定下来了吗
I'm thinking Takarazuka Kinen.
我想应该可以参加宝冢纪念吧
If they choose me, that is.
不过也要被选上才行就是了
Takarazu… On a…
宝冢啊 草上…
Yes?
是
Sorry for the intrusion.
打扰了
Kitasan Black.
北部玄驹 不好意思
Yeah?
是…
Sorry to have come to you this early in the morning.
抱歉一早就来打扰你
Please come to the student council with me.
希望你能跟我去一趟学生会室
Huh?
咦
UMA MUSUME PRETTY DERBY SEASON 3
《赛马娘 Pretty Derby 第三季》
What?
什么
"EPISODE 10: FESTIVAL"
(第10话 祭典)
I'm chairing the executive committee?
要我来当执行委员长
Yes. Are you up for it?
是啊 你能接下来吗
But why me?
可是…为什么要找我呢
We're planning a new event this year.
这次规划了一个新活动
It's an event jointly held by the school and the city council to revive the town.
是由城镇与学园联合举办 同时具有振兴地方效果的活动
"TRACEN ACADEMY-CITY COUNCIL COLLAB" As last year's horse girl of the year,
(特雷森学园地方联合活动) 身为去年年度赛马娘的你
you are the best candidate.
是最适合的人选
Eh?
咦
Besides, you also
而且我还听说
have a nickname that goes by "Festival Girl".
你似乎还有个"祭典女孩"的外号
Well…
这…也是啦
This event is similar to a festival.
这次的活动内容也跟祭典很类似
You are close to the locals so you're the best person for it, Kitasan.
我认为跟当地民众关系良好的北部 很适合担任这个职位
Festival…
祭典…
Yes. I want you to make it festive.
是啊 我希望借助你的力量 炒热气氛
What do you think?
你意下如何
A festival?
祭典是吧
I see. I'll do my best.
我明白了 我会竭尽所能的
TRACEN ACADEMY-CITY COUNCIL COLLAB
(特雷森学园地方联合活动)
HISHI AMAZON: COME TAKE A PHOTO!
(菱亚马逊 欢迎摄影)
KOSHI-IWATE SPECIALITY
(高知 岩手物产展)
EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE MEMBER
(执行委员)
Great.
好
As the chairwoman, I must make this festival a great success.
我身为执行委员长 一定要让活动热闹起来
Morning.
早安
Kita?
小北啊
Great to see you today.
今天请多指教了
Thank you for helping out.
感谢您的帮忙
I count on you for today.
我也要请您多多指教
Running a stall in a school
居然能在学园里做生意
is quite the unique experience.
这感觉还真是奇特
"HAMBURGERS"
(肉汁汉堡 烤秋刀鱼 烤香蕉串)
"GRILLED MACKEREL" It feels good
这种大家一起办活动的感觉很棒呢
"GRILLED BANANA" Yes, do enjoy the festivity too.
是啊 也请各位一起来享受活动吧
I need to get going.
那我先走了
-Good luck. -All the best.
-好 加油哦 -加油
You can do this.
要加油哦
Kita.
小北
Teio?
帝皇
You look so handsome.
好帅哦
Rudolf did it once
以前会长她们有做过
so I want to try it out too.
所以我也想来试着做一次
Are you patrolling, Kita?
小北现在在巡视吗
Yes.
是的
I'm so sorry that I can't help Spica out.
抱歉 没办法来Spica这里帮忙
That can't be helped.
这也是没办法的事
After all, you're the chairwoman of the committee.
毕竟北部你是执行委员长嘛
We can handle this. You focus on your work.
这里就交给我们 你就去忙委员长的工作吧
If you're free later, come and have some tea with us.
晚点有时间的话 再来这里喝茶吧
Thank you so much.
谢谢大家
I'll wait for you with hot tea.
我会泡好茶等你的
Gold Ship?
黄金船…
Eh?
咦
Baaaa.
咩…
A sheep?
羊
Wear your uniform already!
你快去把衣服穿好啦
Do you even know the theme of our cafe here?
你到底懂不懂我们在开什么店啊
Let me be. I want to dress up like this.
少啰嗦 我就要这样穿
A butler should wear a sheep overall.
说到执事就是要穿羊装啊
What the heck?
你在胡说什么啦…
TRACEN ACADEMY-CITY COUNCIL COLLAB PATROL ROUTE
(特雷森学园地方联合活动) (巡视路线 户外摊位 女神像前) (跟商店街的大家打招呼 校舍1楼) (Spica的各位 光钻&皇冠)
SAY HI TO EVERYONE FROM THE COMMERCIAL STREET
那个…再来是…
Welcome.
欢迎光临…
Would you like to visit Maid Cafe by Satonos?
要来里见家的女仆咖啡厅坐坐吗
"MAID CAFE BY SATONOS" Would you like to
(女仆咖啡厅 里见之馆)
Diamond.
光钻
Kita.
小北
You look so cute in this outfit, Diamond.
光钻你穿这样好可爱哦
You too, Crown.
皇冠也是
Capella's trainer
Capella的训练师…
still looks the same.
则是跟平常一样呢
Thank you for your hard work as the chairwoman.
担任执行委员长 辛苦你了
Kitasan, you're participating in Takarazuka Kinen, aren't you?
北部 你也会参加 这次的宝冢纪念对吧
Even though I lost to you in the fans' voting,
虽然粉丝投票输给了你
I won't lose to you during the race.
不过比赛我可不会输哦
Me neither. I won't lose to you.
才不呢 我也不会输给你的
I will cheer for you two.
我会替你们两位加油的
Eh? You're not joining, Diamond?
咦 光钻不参加吗
Diamond wants to take a break.
光钻要暂时休息一下
I thought about it for a long time.
我思考了很久
This autumn, I have to give my all.
我想要在今年秋天 赌上我的一切
For Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe, right?
准备参加凯旋门赏 对吧
Oh, Diamond…
光钻…
I see.
这样啊…
I'll go back to my patrol duty then.
那我就继续去巡视了
Okay.
嗯
Good luck.
加油哦
HIT THE BELLY BUTTON TO WIN THE PRIZE
(打中肚脐可得奖品)
THROWING GAME
(投掷挑战)
W... What?
什…什么
Strike!
好
You're good. Here you go.
真是厉害 拿去吧
Thank you.
谢谢
You can have this.
给你
You have improved.
身手进步了呢
I can't get complacent, can I?
毕竟我总不能一直停留在原地
As expected from fans' third favourite in Takarazuka Kinen.
真不愧是宝冢纪念 粉丝投票第三名
Third…
可是第三名…
Third again.
又是第三名…
Welcome.
欢迎光临…
"COOKIE CARVE-NIVAL" Come.
(雕糖饼) 来
Dura.
小鸣
Kitasan Black.
北部玄驹
What a shame. You were so close.
好可惜哦 就差一点点了
I can't wing it.
很难随心所欲呢
So, did you have fun today?
如何 今天玩得开心吗
Yes, it's the perfect break for someone who does physiotherapy every day like me.
是啊 是个适合每天复健的我 出来透透气的活动
I heard you are the chairwoman.
听说你是这次的执行委员长
How is everything?
状况如何
Well, I'm enjoying it.
嗯 很开心
Everyone is smiling
大家脸上都是满满的笑容
and that makes me feel energized.
也让我很有精神
I see.
这样啊…
This is the view you created.
这是你创造出来的景色
Huh?
咦
I… I'm not that good yet.
没有啦 我没那么厉害啦
But you can still…
但是 你应该还能更加地…
Huh?
咦
One day, I'll create a view as good as… No.
我有朝一日 也要创造出不输给你…
A view more memorable than yours.
不 是创造出比现在更加耀眼的光景
When I win Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe.
就在我赢下凯旋门赏之时
Your dream hasn't changed at all, Dura.
小鸣的梦想还是没变呢
Yes.
是啊
I'll prove that I'm the best horse girl
证明我是最强
and everyone in Japan will cheer loudly for me.
并绝对要让全日本 为之兴奋 疯狂与欢腾
Everyone in Japan, huh…
全日本吗…
Welcome.
欢迎光临…
-Come. -What do you think?
-来 -如何
If I win,
如果获胜的话…
everyone will smile from the bottom of their heart.
日本的所有人将会展露笑容 开心大笑 热闹非凡
Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe is capable of doing that, right?
凯旋门赏就是如此厉害的比赛对吧
Yes.
当然了
You will earn a page in the history books.
可说是会写进历史的壮举吧
I see.
这样啊…
The view will definitely surpass the current one…
会比现在这个景色更加地…
Chairwoman Kitasan Black.
北部玄驹执行委员长
You are required in the office tent immediately.
请速至总部帐篷
I have to go now.
我得走了
Bye, Dura.
再见了 小鸣
Enjoy the festival.
你好好享受吧
Okay.
好
SHAKY SHAKY RAMEN
(美妙姿势拉面)
BANANA EATING COMPETITION
(香蕉大胃王对决)
COPANO RICKEY'S FENGSHUI YOUR FUTURE IN A BALL
(小林历奇风水) (有占无患)
POWER AND BEAUTY: NEW CHAMPION UNIFORM FASHION SHOW
(力与美 新胜负服走秀会)
FISH GOLDFISH FISH WATER BALLOON
(捞金鱼 钓水球)
ANIMAL PARK
(动物抚摸广场)
Hello.
打扰了
Mr. Trainer.
训练师先生
Oh, Kitasan.
哦 北部
Nice work today. What's up?
你今天辛苦了 怎么啦
The campfire party is about to begin.
营火晚会差不多要开始了
Gold Ship asked me to invite you.
黄金船她们要我来叫你过去
They are going to do something wild.
反正她们就只想让我去买单吧
I'm too old for that already.
我哪奉陪得了 真是的
Eh?
咦
This is my…
这个是我的…
Yes. I wanted to read it.
是啊…想说来看一下
Is this my debut?
这是出道赛吗
This is my second race.
这是我的第二战
This is from Spring Stakes.
而这是春季锦标赛的时候的…
Who would have thought that you'd head into the classics with three wins?
想不到你能以三连胜进入经典赛
But I wasn't very popular back then.
不过我那个时候的人气不高呢
Satsuki Sho and Derby…
皋月赏与德比
It was a very difficult period. Defeating too.
那个时候真的很痛苦 很难过
Yes, but you survived it.
但是你都跨越过去了
St. Leger Stakes.
圣烈治纪念赛
And Kikuka Sho.
还有…菊花赏
Arima Kinen and Osaka Hai.
有马纪念与大阪杯
My first Tenno Sho in Spring.
初次参加的春季天皇赏
And Takarazuka Kinen.
还有宝冢纪念
During the Kyoto Daishoten, you were the most popular horse girl.
在京都大赏典时 你第一次成为最高人气赛马娘呢
I was so nervous back then for some reason.
那个时候不知道为什么 紧张得不得了
Then, I won Japan Cup.
赢下日本杯
I raced with Diamond in my second Takarazuka Kinen.
在第二次的宝冢纪念里 跟光钻一起比赛
I was in a lot of tournaments.
我参加了…很多的比赛呢
Yes, you were.
是啊 一点也没错
And next up is Takarazuka Kinen?
而这次是宝冢纪念吗
Yes.
是的
No horse girl has been able to obtain triple crown as a veteran.
尚没有任何赛马娘达成的 "春季资深三冠"
It's a physically demanding feat.
虽然是会消耗不少体力的连续赛事
But I know you can do it.
但你一定没问题的
Mr. Trainer.
训练师先生
Yeah?
嗯
I will win Takarazuka Kinen.
我会赢下宝冢纪念的
Then, I want to
然后我想要去挑战
go international.
挑战海外赛事
I've been thinking about
我思考了很久
what I can do to make everyone happier.
思考我还要去做什么 才能够让大家更加开心
I thought that by carrying everyone's hopes and dreams
我认为背负着众人的思念以及心愿 期待还有梦想
while I pass the finishing line
带着这些上场比赛奔跑
as the first place, I would have my answer.
以首位之姿冲过终点的前方 就会有我所追求的答案
-Burn brighter. -Everyone is smiling.
-火焰啊…燃烧吧… -大家一起展露笑容
-They have fun. They enjoy the moment.
-开心大笑 热闹欢腾
-Burn brighter. -It's like a festival.
-火焰啊…燃烧吧… -就像祭典一样…
I want to create that moment.
我想创造这样的光景
I see.
这样啊…
I get it now.
我明白了
I'll help you sign up for Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe.
我来帮你办理参加凯旋门赏的手续
Thank you.
谢谢您
Well, Mr. Trainer,
那么训练师先生
the campfire party has begun.
营火晚会已经开始了
Hurry up now. Everyone's waiting for you.
大家都在等着你 要快点来哦
UMA MUSUME PRETTY DERBY SEASON 3
《赛马娘 Pretty Derby 第三季》
Really? You're participating in Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe too?
真的吗 小北也要去参加凯旋门赏吗
Yes. I've been thinking about it.
是啊 我想了很久
You need to recover faster then.
那就得快点治好感冒才行了呢
Yes.
嗯
You must have overworked yourself.
一定是因为你太劳累了
After the festival, you can rest.
在活动结束后整个放松了下来
I guess.
可能是吧…
I'm off then.
那我就出发了
Take care.
路上小心
Thank you for your guidance.
感谢您的关照
What happened?
她是怎么了啊
I think she is quitting.
我想…应该是退出了吧
Eh.
咦
It's common to see horse girls quit after they reach their ceilings.
察觉自己的极限而退出的赛马娘 是很常见的事情
I see.
这样啊…
Lie down now and rest well.
那你要乖乖躺着把病治好
All right?
知道吗
Oh, Diamond.
啊 对了 光钻
Can I borrow something?
我想要跟你借个东西
Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe.
凯旋门赏
"DIAMOND'S READING REGARDING THE PRIX" Held in France in autumn,
(光钻的凯旋门赏相关书籍) 在秋天于法国举办的这项赛事
this grand event gathers
是聚集各国德比赛马娘
all Derby horse girls.
以及一流GI赛马娘的 世界最高峰赛事
"PAST JAPANESE CHALLENGERS" Japanese horse girls have signed up for it
(挑战凯旋门赏的日本赛马娘们) 是日本赛马娘过去也曾多次挑战
but they all lost.
但最终都败下阵来的最强决定战
If I win in this race,
若能这场比赛中胜出
I will literally overwrite the Japanese racing history.
就代表改变日本赛马娘历史 这么说也一点都不为过
A grand event, huh?
世界最高峰…
It sounds daunting.
这果然是很不得了的比赛呢…
If I participate in it…
我若是要参加的话…
No, to win it, I…
不对 为了赢得胜利…
All right then.
好
Sorry for the trouble, everyone.
抱歉让大家担心了
Are you fully recovered?
身体已经没问题了吗
Yes, I am.
是 已经完全康复了
Don't force yourself now. It'll be bad if your cold comes back.
别太勉强自己 要是感冒复发就麻烦了
I'm fine. I only need a good sleep to treat something as trivial as a cold.
没问题的 那种小病只要睡一天就能康复了
Either way, I have to catch up for my missed training yesterday.
总之我要连昨天的份一起跑回来
You just recovered from a cold. Don't push yourself too far.
你才刚大病初愈 别太勉强自己了
I know… But if I don't work hard enough,
是…但是我要是不努力的话
I won't be able to create a festive wave.
是无法在全日本掀起祭典热潮的
A festive wave?
祭典热潮
Yes, a festive wave.
没错 祭典热潮
All right. Another lap then.
好 我再去跑一趟
Wait!
你等等…
"BIG SONG BAR" Kitasan wants to compete internationally?
(酒吧 Big Song) 北部想要挑战海外赛事
Yes.
是啊…
But you don't look too thrilled about it.
但你看起来却不怎么开心呢
You're against the decision?
你反对吗
I do think that she has what it takes to compete internationally.
我倒是认为她拥有能够向其挑战 的成绩与实力
Truth be told, I feel uneasy.
老实说我很不安
It's a long race, unlike any other race we have here.
跟国内赛事 完全无法相比的长距离移动
I also wonder if Japanese horse girls can get used to their turf.
也很担心日本赛马娘 和那边草地的适性
Not to mention that I have to hand a lot of things over to a foreign trainer.
还有很多事情 得交给那边的训练师去做
Many are horse girls whose growth was stumped
太过勉强自己 去参加不熟悉的海外赛事
because they forced themselves to adapt to a foreign environment.
结果因此实力大减的赛马娘 不在少数
It's not uncommon.
这种事是很常发生的
Besides…
而且…
Never mind.
不 没什么…
Ow.
好痛…
Cheer up.
你要振作一点
You can't beat yourself up like this.
怎么能连你都说出这种丧气话
Yes, before we make the decision, only God knows what's good for us.
是啊 在做出决定之前 只有神才知道什么是正确答案
If you want to know more about international races, you can ask her.
如果是海外相关问题的话 那要不要找她讨论看看呢
Sorry, I'm late.
抱歉 我迟到了
Hello, what would you like to order?
辛苦了 要来点什么呢
Uhm…
这个嘛…
They have milk here too.
这里也有牛奶哦
In that case…
那么…
Tequila straight, in a tankard.
龙舌兰不加冰 用啤酒杯装
Eh?
咦…
MOUNT KINTOKI, SUMMIT, 1,212M ABOVE SEA LEVEL
(金时山 山顶 标高1212米)
Spring G1 has ended.
好的 今年春季的GI赛事 也将告一个段落
The grand event, Takarazuka Kinen, is about to begin.
大奖赛 宝冢纪念 马上就要开始了
The most popular and also
人气压倒性位居第一的
the fans' favourite, Kitasan Black, is here.
是同时也是粉丝投票冠军的 北部玄驹
She won Osaka Hai and Tenno Sho. If she wins this, she'll have the triple crown.
毕竟赢下了大阪杯 春季天皇赏 再赢下这场就是春季资深三冠了
I can't wait to see her performance later.
非常期待她在赛场上的精彩表现
I will win this race and go to France.
我一定要赢下这场比赛 然后去法国
I will win this G1 race.
我今天要在这里 赢下国内的GI胜利
I must win.
我要获胜
I don't want to live in regrets again.
不能再让自己陷在懊悔的情绪之中
I have to win.
无论如何都一定要赢
Kitasan Black enters the horse gate calmly.
好的 北部玄驹相当沉静地 缓缓走入闸门
Satono Crown is the last to enter the gate.
最后走入的是里见皇冠
After a heavy rain, this grand event in Hanshin Racecourse
大雨过后的阪神竞马场大奖赛
begins now.
比赛开始
All horse girls bolt out at the same time.
各赛马娘同时起跑
Kitasan Black is off to a beautiful start.
北部玄驹的起跑也相当漂亮
She's trying to get the lead.
现在在争夺领先位置
Flying Turkey charges out and…
飞行火鸡冲了出来…
What? Cheval Grand is in the lead.
什么 居然是高尚骏逸取得了领先
What a surprise from Cheval Grand.
高尚骏逸居然如此大胆
Behind her is Moon Hero.
在她后面的是明月英雄
Then, it's Kitasan Black.
后方就是北部玄驹
She secures a good spot.
她抢到了一个好位置
Cheval?
骏逸
No, I must maintain my tempo.
不 我要维持我的步调
On the inside line is Ribbon Gavotte.
最内侧的是缎带加沃特
Opheryu and Satono Crown are in the middle.
而在中间的是巨星俳优 以及里见皇冠
Then, it's Ribbon Pastoral. Seventh Queen is on the flank.
接着是缎带牧歌 外侧则是第七女王
Behind them are Brave Target and Original Shine.
后方则是勇气标的和原初闪亮
Onward to the first bend,
现在进入第一弯道
I wonder what Cheval Grand's plan is to maintain his lead.
拔得头筹的高尚骏逸 不知她的心里有着何种战术
Despite losing her lead, Kitasan Black
被夺去领先地位的北部玄驹
continues to run for her third G1 victory.
正朝向春季GI3连胜 气势如虹地飞驰而去
The horse girls are heading to the stretch.
各赛马娘即将进入非终点直线
Cheval Grand still has the lead.
领先的是大胆抢下第一的高尚骏逸
Half a length behind her is Moon Hero.
半马身后方的是明月英雄
Kitasan Black is on the flank. She's in the third place today.
她的外侧是北部玄驹 今天的她在第三名位置
Satono Crown closes in.
里见皇冠接近她了
Kitasan hasn't accelerated.
北部没有上前呢
Indeed.
是啊
This is not her usual self.
这个状态还挺不像她的作风呢
I'm sure Kitasan will do just fine.
北部的话 一定没有问题的
The first 1,000-meter lap was completed in 1.06 minutes.
最初的1000米 时间为1分0秒6
-The race is slower than before. -If I accelerate now…
-整体步调比之前来得要慢 -好 如果要出手的话…
Here!
就是这里
After the third bend, everyone starts to accelerate.
过了第三弯道 所有人渐渐加快了步调
Cheval Continue still takes the lead.
但现在依然是高尚骏逸领先
On the flank is Moon Hero.
她的外侧则是明月英雄
Then, Kitasan Black.
再来是北部玄驹
When will she accelerate? Can she overtake others?
她会在哪里出手 又会如何力压其他赛马娘呢
This is weird.
奇怪…
Nothing. Kitasan Black still hasn't shown anything.
没有动作 北部玄驹现在还是没有任何动作
Cheval Grand slowly widens the gap.
高尚骏逸慢慢拉开差距
Satono Crown and Original Shine approach from the flank.
里见皇冠和原初闪亮 从外侧追了上来
Is Opheryu trying to overtake them from the inside line?
而巨星俳优则是要从内侧超越吗
All horse girls have merged into a group now.
好的 选手们挤在了一团
They pass the final bend en masse.
赛马娘挤成了一团 弯过了最终弯道
Kitasan Black charges in.
北部玄驹径直往直线奔去
-Go, Kitasan! -Kitasan Black charges in.
-冲啊 北部 -北部玄驹径直往直线奔去
Moon Hero is in first place now.
第一名换成了明月英雄
Satono Crown and Kitasan Black close in from the flank.
里见皇冠和北部玄驹 从外侧追了上来
Onto the final stretch.
进入最后的直线
Can Kitasan Black outrun everyone?
北部玄驹有办法突破重围 冲过终点吗
What? Kitasan Black is panting?
什么 北部玄驹居然气喘吁吁
Kitasan Black cannot accelerate. She can't.
北部玄驹无法加速 快不起来
She lost her burst.
她没有了以往的爆发力
Why?
为什么
Satono Crown slowly closes in from the flank.
就在这时里见皇冠 逐渐从外侧逼近
Kitasan Black slowed down.
北部玄驹慢了下来
The fans' favourite, Kitasan Black, is losing.
有着压倒性人气的北部玄驹 败下阵来了
Satono Crown goes shoulder-to-shoulder and continues running forward.
里见皇冠像是交换位置般 不断冲上前
Satono Crown overtook her!
里见皇冠超越了
Opheryu is on the inside line.
内侧是巨星俳优
Seventh Queen chases behind her from the flank.
外侧则是第七女王紧追在后
Oh, Satono Crown.
然而 里见皇冠
She wants to leave them behind and she sprints!
以有如要甩开她们一般 全力进行着末段冲刺
Satono Crown. It's Satono Crown!
里见皇冠 是里见皇冠
Satono Crown finishes the race in first place.
里见皇冠以领先之姿冲过终点
Opheryu takes second.
第二名是巨星俳优
Seventh Queen is third.
第三名是第七女王
I can't believe Satono Crown won.
想不到获胜的竟然会是里见皇冠
Kitasan Black was defeated.
北部玄驹败下阵来
I did it.
成功了
I won!
我成功了
I did it!
我做到了
Congratulations, Crown.
皇冠 恭喜你
How can this be?
奇怪…